

dawid@zbinski.eu ⊠
zbinski.dev □

Žilina, Slovakia

+421 **951 297 380**

BIOGRAPHY

My journey in software development began when I was 11 years old and learned the basics of Pascal. After that came PHP, HTML & CSS which led me to the web development. When I finished the high school I wanted to find my first job to make the money and pay my studies. I found one in Ringier Axel Springer where I was responsible for Bistro.sk and its sub-projects.

With me on site, we did rework most of our front-end in the sub-projects and created a REST API for making our platform accessible and easier to maintain. This gave us an opportunity to use the front-end frameworks like Vue.js as well as maintain code for multiple applications in one palce. I was responsible mainly for creating the REST API in Symfony, creating and maintaining Vue.js SPA for restaurants' administration, creating a Node.js web socket server which was deployed in Docker Swarm and many others.

When it comes to my career as a freelancer I had the opportunity to create the Vue.js + Three.js application for modeling and pricing the wardrobes, multiple REST APIs in Symfony and few of them in Node.js, 360° Image Viewer and 3D Model Loader for GLTF format in order to display models on the web. And, of course, I'm still waiting for more to come...

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Web development

JavaScript
PHP
SQL
Vue.js
Angular
Symfony
HTML / Twig

CSS & pre-processors
WebGL (Three.js)
Unit tests (Jest, PHPUnit)

E2E tests

Docker

Others

Responsive Web Design

UX Design & Consulting

Performance Optimization

Docker & Docker stack

Documentation Web WebVR

UI/UX Design

OpenSource Software

Google Cloud Services

Data Optimization

Documentation writing

EXPERIENCE

From March 2019

FREELANCER

Dawid Grzegorz Zbiński - DEVELOG

From January 2018 to March 2019

WEB DEVELOPER

Ringer Axel Springer SK, a.s.

From January 2017 to January 2018

WEB DEVELOPER

Ringer Axel Springer Slovakia, a.s.

EDUCATION

From October 2016 to March 2017

Computer Science

Akademia Górniczo-Hutnicza im. Stanisława Staszica, Kraków, Poland

O From September 2012 to May 2016

Information Technology

Súkromná Stredná Odborná Škola Tatranská Akadémia, Poprad, Slovakia

LANGUAGES







HOBBIES & INTERESTS









Gaming

Traveling



Žilina , Slovakia	\Diamond
dawid @zbinski.eu	\boxtimes
zbinski .dev	
+421 951 297 380	

MORE ABOUT MY EXPERIENCE

Ringier Axel Springer SK, a.s.

- Back-end: Symfony, Node.js, RabbitMQ, WebSockets (Socket.io), ...
- Front-end: Web Components, Vue.js, JavaScript ES5+, LESS/SASS, jQuery, ...

I was responsible for most of the Bistro.sk internal projects like Bistro Restaurant Administration, Bistro Driver, and many others. With me on site, we managed to refresh our code-base and split it into the multiple chunks which **resulted in better performance**, **improved quality of the code**, **and created faster**, **scalable**, **and automatic deployment process**. Specifically, I created and managed the following projects (mostly) by myself:

REST API:

- created for Bistro and its subprojects to simplify infrastructure, create re-usable, shared & centralized code across all the projects
- built mostly on PHP stack (Symfony 4.2, Doctrine ORM, Redis + Sentinel, SwiftMailer, Twig, etc.)
- strictly **followed the REST specification** in order to create maintainable code
- optimized Symfony for Read-only environments (which is pretty tricky)
- created full CI/CD (Gitlab) for testing, building & deploying the project
- built (from scratch) on top of Alpine Linux using docker, docker-compose and published inside docker swarm as a stack of services

WebSocket Stack:

- created for services like Bistro Driver for efficient communication between multiple clients
- built on Node.js stack (express, socket.io, amqp) with RabbitMQ & ng-inx
- used amqp protocol with RabbitMQ client to queue all the messages which made the project more scalable
- optimized for more than 500,000 requests per day from multiple sources

Bistro Restaurant Admin:

- created for the restaurants to give them the ability to analyze their sales and manage their presence on Bistro.sk
- built mostly on Vue.js stack (Vue.js, Vuex, Vue Router, Vue CLI)
- development env. configured and set up using **Webpack & Babel**, so we could use some of the functionalities from the new JavaScript versions/proposals which were not supported by the Vue CLI at the moment (optional chaining)

Freelance Projects

- Back-end: Symfony, Node.js
- Front-end: Web Components, Vue.js, JavaScript ES5+, SASS, Angular, Three.js ...

Every offer I accept, I try to make it somehow unique or different from the others, both technically and personally. For each project I always tried to make my best and create a good product for a fair price. Also, each project has its piece of documentation & codebase (unfortunately, not many are public). Some of the recent projects I worked/still working on:

Wardrobe Studio, Mr. Wood FR (wardrobe.zbinski.dev - not finished yet):

- 3D web studio which gives the user an ability to create their own wardrobe with custom sizes/textures/spaces
- built from scratch using Three.js, Vue.js & Vuex
- optimized rendering of the textures by optimizing WebGL loaders, texture sizes/formats and garbage collection of JavaScript

3D Viewer, AR Visual s.r.o. (not published yet):

- 3D viewer for models in GLTF format in Three.js, which was later replaced by the model-viewer web component
- custom logic implemented in Three.js underneath the model-viewer (live texture replacements, etc.)

360° Picture Viewer, AR Visual s.r.o. (kavehome-preview.zbinski.dev):

- custom image viewer which loads the images taken from different angles and makes them interactive similar to the 3D model
- built from scratch in Vue.js + TypeScript + Three.js and exported as a Web Component

Websites, Multiple Clients (civicko.sk | pensionvasko.sk | zdiarholidaycottage.sk):

- simple websites for services built using Symfony, Doctrine ORM, JavaScript ES6+, ...
- implemented payment gateways like GoPay/Espago
- worked on SEO and helped with SEM/SM campaigns

and many other smaller projects ...



Žilina , Slovakia	\bigcirc
dawid @zbinski.eu	\bowtie
zbinski .dev	
+421 951 297 380	

OPEN-SOURCE EXPERIENCE

I try to help the community from which I learned so much by contributing and creating open-source projects, and by helping others on forums like stackoverflow.com.

GitHub: flyrell

StackOverflow: Dawid Zbiński (top 10% of contributors in 2019)

axios-auth-refresh (npmjs.com/axios-auth-refresh)

- simple library written in TypeScript for refreshing the authorization when using Axios HTTP client

ng-dragonly [unmaintained] (npmjs.com/ng-dragonly):

- browser-agnostic angular module with directive that can be palced on any html element and make it movable on the website

rest-api-url-builder:

- very simple url builder

Contributed to: Symfony, Silex, js-tabby, axios, onepage-scroll, vue-date-picker, vue2-gmap-custom-marker, ...

I was the part of the core mentor team at **Azet Academy**, the program by Ringier Axel Springer SK, a.s., created to teach people to program in less than 3 months. I was responsible for creating the timeline and the content of the academy and in 2019 I became a leader of it. The fields I was focused on (mainly) are **Docker, Software Architecture, Network Communication, Security and last, but not least, Front-end technologies.**